PABLO BIEDMA NUNEZ

pablobiedma.github.io

+8615701094592 pablobie00@gmail.com



PERSONAL PROFILE

Throughout the entirety of my academic career, I have devoted myself to bridging the gap between humans and computers by designing intelligent systems that can be purposely used by mankind. I am a Computer Science graduate student (*Tsinghua University*) currently interning for **Microsoft Research Asia**, and recently named "*Top Software Engineering Talent Under 25*" by TNW.

EDUCATION

PUBLICATIONS

2024 - Beyond Human Norms: Unveiling Unique Values of Large Language Models through Interdisciplinary Approaches (CoNLL, *under review*).

2022 - Who Cares About Fairness: How Background Influences the Way Practitioners Consider Machine Learning Harms (*Bachelor thesis*).

ACHIEVEMENTS & AWARDS

2024	Participant at the United Nations' GESC 2024, Tongji University, Shanghai		
	KUSE and AI for Research Workshop Participant at the Embassy of the Republic of Ecuador, China		
2023	O23 Top 500 talent Under 25 in Software Engineering by TNW		
	MIMIC2023 Elite Cybersecurity Challenge Finalist, Nanjing, China		
	Spanish National Cybersecurity League Finals (classified 3rd out of 400)		
	Interaction Film Program participant in Čačak, Serbia		
2022	Semifinalist in the Philips Innovation Award		

- Directed an award-winning short film presented at a Short Film Festival in Arnhem, Netherlands Invited to attend The Next Web Conference in Amsterdam
- 2021 Finalist of the 4TU Challenge
 Ultrahack Metaverse Hackathon winner in Pori, Finland
 TU Delft Impact Contest Winner
- Top Talent Under 25 in the Digital World by Variety
 Covered +10 International film festivals as press including Cannes, Berlin, and Venice
 NASA International Space Apps Challenge participant
 EUvs Virus Challenge participant
- Certificate of Appreciation from Steven Wilson, Head of Europol's European Cybercrime Center
 Winner of the "The Hague International Cyber Security Challenge"
 Winner of "YesDelft: The Voice of Holland" pitching competition
- 2018 Co-created one of the largest online film magazines in Spain (cinemacoloris.com)
 Winner of the "Algeciras Scientific Poetry Contest"
 Third place for 'Best Digital Project' at "Diverciencias"
 Winner of the "Los Pinos" literary contest
- 2017 Became a certified technician in First Aid Rescue and lifeguard Semi-Finalist of the **Audi** Innovation Challenge High performance certificate in Cyber Security Carlos III University, Madrid

WORK EXPERIENCE

07/2024 - 09/2024 Research Intern

*Microsoft*Beijing, China

I contributed to the field of value evaluation in LLMs at Microsoft's Social Computing group where I wrote a paper in which I served as first author.

10/2022 - 04/2023 Software Engineering Intern

BMW

Munich, Germany

At BMW's Emerging Technologies department, I worked on cryptography in distributed systems by implementing Secure Multi-Party Computation into real-world applications.

05/2023 - 07/2023 Data Engineering Intern

Lufthansa

Frankfurt, Germany

I created a data pipeline integrating real-time updates through Azure functions. Furthermore, I established a live Tableau connection for dynamic metric visualization.

OTHER ACADEMIC ACTIVITIES

- 2023 Baxter Robot Revival by Deep Learning application at Riga Technical University, Latvia (6 ECTS)
- 2022 Venice International University Summer School Filming Venice, Italy (4 ECTS)
- 2021 Entrepreneurship as part of TU Delft impact contest (3 ECTS)
- 2020 Finalist at the Falling Walls Lab Delft (Research competition)
 Chair of the Board of Directors of the Student Council at the TU Delft
- 2019 Invited to attend a conference on Cyber Norms by The Hague Program for Cyber Norms Conducted research for **Europol** on data insertion in Bitcoin blockchain Gave a **TED** talk competing for the TEDxDelft Award
- Volunteered at the **ESA** (European Space Agency) open days (Leiden, Netherlands) Runner-up "Algeciras Best Young Researcher"
- 2017 Attended the European Cybersecurity Challenge (Malaga, Spain)
 Conducted research on Bioinspired Robotics for natural disaster detection at La Salle University
- 2016 Finalist of the Barcelona International Youth Science Challenge

SCHOLARSHIPS, GRANTS & PRIZES

- 2023 Mimic Elite International Cybersecurity Competition Finals, Nanjing (Sponsored by THU, China)
- 2022 Raised \$2500 to cover the 2022 San Sebastian International Film Festival
- 2022 Won \$300 at the HSIF pitching competition (Den Haag, Netherlands)
- 2021 Raised \$1000 for "Filmmate" a movie database with user interaction capabilities.
- 2018 Won \$200 in the "Los Pinos" literary contest
- 2014 Won \$400 as a runner-up in the 2014 Gibraltar Junior International Chess Festival
- 2013 Received a government scholarship after winning the U-12 regional chess championship

REFERENCES

Maosong Sun	Dhruv Mehta	Xing Xie
Professor	Assistant Professor	Research Manager
Tsinghua University	Delft University of Technology	Microsoft Research Asia
sms@tsinghua.edu.cn	d.mehta@tudelft.nl	xing.xie@microsoft.com